# **KECHI BONIFACE**

UI ENGINEER / WEB ACCESSIBILITY ANALYST

## **DETAILS**

#### ADDRESS

Borough of Queens, 11433 United States

#### PHONE

3477403150

#### **EMAIL**

bonifacekechi@gmail.com

#### PLACE OF BIRTH

New York

#### LINKS

<u>website</u>

#### SKILLS

WAI-ARIA, HTML5

QA Accessibility Testing Tools – Assistive technologies (screen readers -JAWS & NVDA, Voiceover, Talkback, Chrome-VOX), Keyboard, Browser Automated Testing, Color Contrast Analyzer, Dragon Naturally Speaking, ZoomText, axe DevTools

IAAP (CPACC) Certified Professional in Accessibility Core Competencies

Document Accessibility: Email Accessibility, Microsoft Office Accessibility, PDF, InDesign, Epub

Front-end Frameworks: React, Vue, Angular, Next, Gatsby, JQuery

CSS: LESS, SASS, Animista, CSS Gradient, Styled Components,

UI Frameworks: Bootstrap, Material UI, Tailwind CSS, Bulma

Section 508 Compliance DHS Trusted Tester W.I.I.I Certification

## **PROFILE**

Dedicated self-starter positively changing how millions of people who use assistive technology interact with enterprise applications, making them more engaging, personalized, and inclusive. With extensive experience in working with various assistive technologies and in-depth knowledge of Section 508 and the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines as well as over 3 years of solid background in hand-coding HTML and CSS, I excel in identifying, analyzing, and remediating WCAG violations. I have developed excellent user-focused, solution-driven strategies and a keen eye for detail. I am also an effective communicator with the ability to work independently or in a remote team environment. Proven ability to embrace being the 'voice of the customer' when providing consultation, guidance, and mentoring to development and project teams across business units during all phases of the SDLC.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Web Accessibility Developer/Analyst, Capital One

Richmond, VA

Apr 2022 — Apr 2023

- Executed corporate accessibility strategy across various products and services in collaboration with partners and product owners, ensuring adherence to WCAG standards, ARIA best practices, PDF/Universal Accessibility, ADA, Section 508, and the 21st Century Communication and Video Accessibility Act.
- Offer guidance on remediation for non-conforming products and provide remediation services when needed.
- Conducted comprehensive accessibility audits to identify gaps and recommended effective solutions to enhance accessibility compliance.
- Developed custom training programs and created documentation and hosted Accessibility Office Hours providing mentorship and coaching to Product Designers, UI/UX Designers, and Developers to facilitate and incorporate accessibility throughout the design process based on emerging standards and technologies, enabling broader accessibility adoption.
- Provide guidance on procurement of information and communications technology (ICT) and development of ICT, including software, and websites.
- Update testing methodology for Section 508 based on recent updates to the Section 508 technical standards.
- Refined and updated internal Accessibility Design tools and frameworks as needed, ensuring they align with industry standards and best practices to further enhance the understanding of accessibility and inclusive design.
- Successfully managed and configured automated accessibility testing platforms, resulting in a 25% reduction in accessibility issues across all digital properties.
- Developed and implemented a testing plan for user testing through third parties, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement and satisfaction.
- Provided training to internal digital teams on using automated testing tools, conducting design reviews, and performing manual testing, resulting in a 20% increase in overall team efficiency and accuracy.
- Established and tracked ongoing mandatory accessibility training for digital project teams, resulting in a 15% increase in attendance and completion rates.
- Created and maintained an intranet with best practices documentation, State
  of Accessibility Reports, and a calendar of events, resulting in a 50% increase
  in accessibility awareness and compliance.
- Developed and coordinated 15+ training-related materials and learning sessions in a corporate environment, resulting in 30% employee engagement and understanding of accessibility methods and standards.
- Provided support and office hours as a subject matter expert, resulting in a 95% satisfaction rate among internal stakeholders and end users.

Jul 2021 — Apr 2022

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams throughout the product design life-cycle, advocating for accessibility in the design system and driving accessibility initiatives.
- Demonstrated proficiency in assistive technologies, including Screen Readers (JAWS, Voice-over, NVDA, Chrome-VOX), Keyboard Accessibility,
- Developed and implemented an updated testing methodology for Section 508 compliance, incorporating recent updates to the Section 508 technical standards, resulting in more accurate and comprehensive accessibility assessments.
- Successfully assessed and remediated information and communications technology (ICT) projects for accessibility, ensuring compliance with Section 508 standards and external guidelines such as Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG).
- Applied UX and Product Design fundamentals, including visual design principles like color, typography, and layout, to create accessible and visually appealing experiences.
- Played a key role in the implementation of the Section 508 standards refresh, identifying and executing process changes, including exceptions and references to external standards, resulting in a 30% increase in accessibility compliance across the organization.
- Review proposed policies, regulations, and procedural changes to assess their impact on areas of responsibility, including updates to the Section 508 policy.
- Proficiently used design and prototyping tools, such as Figma, to create accessible design solutions and prototypes.
- Create and deliver training programs for software developers, program managers, and designers on technical topics such as Section 508, Quality Assurance, and software development technologies.
- Utilized a proactive approach to exploring multiple directions before finalizing design solutions, ensuring optimal accessibility and usability.
- Designed and implemented user interfaces for high-volume transactional e-commerce websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement and satisfaction.
- Built responsive user interfaces for a broad range of devices and screen sizes, resulting in a 20% increase in mobile user engagement.
- Applied Agile methodologies in product management, encompassing testing, documentation, and defect prioritization to maintain high accessibility standards.
- Provided technical consultation to clients, offering guidance on issue resolution, process development, and content governance to improve accessibility practices.
- Collaborated with clients to define testing environments, requirements, and goals, conducting a range of automated, manual, and assistive technology-based tests.
- Prepared comprehensive reports and documentation of accessibility audits and test results, facilitating clear communication and follow-up with clients.
- Successfully implemented modern JavaScript libraries and frameworks, adhering to coding best practices, resulting in a 15% improvement in site performance and reliability.
- Demonstrated adept skills in Microsoft Office suite, including PowerPoint, Excel, Outlook, and Word, resulting in efficient and effective communication with internal and external stakeholders.

# Full Stack Web Developer, Marmalade Al

remote

May 2021 — Jul 2021

- Advised an Agile (Scrum) Development Team to deliver regular updates to the team, resulting in a 25% increase in team velocity.
- Collaborated with UX/UI design teammates to improve the existing applications and increase conversion rate by 15%.
- Modernized the website from WordPress to Vue.js framework, resulting in a 50% improvement in site speed and a 20% increase in user engagement.
- Implemented stand-alone functions that improved the codebase maintainability and allowed for faster feature development by 30%.
- Configured templating for faster compilation and developing reusable components, leading to a 40% reduction in development time.

- Utilized Webpack to execute linters, magnifiers, pre/post-processors, tests, transpires, etc, improving code quality and preventing bugs by 30%.
- Delegated cross-browser/platform compatibility issues (IE, Firefox, and Safari), resulting in a 95% reduction in customer complaints related to browser issues.
- Launched fast dynamic web pages using HTML 5, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SASS, Vue.js, and Firebase, resulting in a 45% increase in user engagement and a 25% increase in conversion rate.
- Instructed lessons on Functional and Technical Knowledge about basic Web Development and how to track the status of the project, resulting in a 90% satisfaction rate from trainees.
- Conducted design mock ups and prototypes for web applications, improving the design process and reducing design errors by 40%.

## EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) - Liberal Arts and Sciences, Lehman College, CUNY

Bronx, NY